<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Saison on Wallflower Brewing</title>
    <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/saison/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Saison on Wallflower Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 16:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/saison/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hoppy Saisonstein Saison</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/hoppy-saisonstein-saison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/hoppy-saisonstein-saison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a bit of a saison kick lately, starting mixed fermentation batches in &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/saison-vinifera&#34;&gt;April&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/rustic-saison&#34;&gt;May&lt;/a&gt;. Those are still bulk aging with probably a few months left to go before bottling. In the meantime, I feel like experimenting with a quicker 100% Saccharomyces saison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to try out a new yeast for this brew, Omega &lt;a href=&#34;https://omegayeast.com/yeast/hybrids/saisonsteins-monster&#34;&gt;Saisonstein&amp;rsquo;s Monster&lt;/a&gt; (OLY-500). It&amp;rsquo;s a hybrid strain, bred from Belgain and French saison parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across this yeast in Union&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unioncraftbrewing.com/project/rough-draughts-tart-saison/&#34;&gt;Tart Saison&lt;/a&gt;, and liked it enough that I thought it was worth a try at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Omega says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Saisonstein] is versatile, aromatic and attenuative with a silky mouthfeel. It excels in high gravity and it ferments more reliably and thoroughly than its parents. It is spicy, complex, tart, dry and crisp with some bubblegum character present from its Belgian parent, and more fruit and fewer phenolics than its French parent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This beer will use a simple recipe to let the yeast shine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Saison I</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/dark-saison-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 12:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/dark-saison-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This batch continues the deep dive I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking into mixed fermentation brewing over the last 6 months. I have a bunch of sours in the pipeline now and I&amp;rsquo;d like to get some funky, non-sour, brett beers going. I brewed my first &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/saison-vinifera&#34;&gt;brett saison&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks ago. This will be my second attempt in the broad style of funky saison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themadfermentationist.com/2019/04/dark-funky-saison-retrospective.html&#34;&gt;10 year retrospective&lt;/a&gt; from The Mad Fermentationist&amp;rsquo;s yearly dark saison project was inspirational. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to keep up my own similar series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the standout beers from that tasting was year four&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themadfermentationist.com/2012/01/american-farmhouse-currant-dark-saison.html&#34;&gt;American Farmhouse Currant Dark Saison&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m going to brew that recipe for the first shot at this style.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saison Vinifera</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/saison-vinifera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 16:11:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/saison-vinifera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vitis_vinifera&#34;&gt;Vitus Vinifera&lt;/a&gt; is the scientific name for the species that contains most varieties of wine grapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &amp;ldquo;Saison Vinifera&amp;rdquo; will blend funky tart saison, oak, and wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/sapwood-saisons-small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bottles of No Beginnings and First Blush&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large portion of my homebrewing over the last six months has been focused on trying to emulate the great mixed fermentation beers coming out of my favorite local brewery, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sapwoodcellars.com&#34;&gt;Sapwood Cellars&lt;/a&gt;. Two of those beers were delicious tart saisons that they released in fall 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Beginnings&lt;/strong&gt; was a pale saison with Brettanomyces, aged in Sauvignon Blanc wine barrels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be willing to bet that &lt;strong&gt;First Blush&lt;/strong&gt; started life as a similar base beer to No Beginnings, but it was fermented with chardonnay &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomace&#34;&gt;pomace&lt;/a&gt;, and finished on whole Cabernet Franc grapes. It is rosé in appearance and the flavor has a unqiue light, tart fruitiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan is to brew a batch of funky pale saison, split it half in secondary, and see how close to each of these I can get&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>