<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pale on Wallflower Brewing</title>
    <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/pale/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pale on Wallflower Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 18:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/pale/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pale Lambic-ish Sour</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/pale-lambic-ish-sour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/pale-lambic-ish-sour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/pale-sour/aging.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;aging beer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year was my first serious year of brewing funky and sour beers. A lot of what I brewed was aiming for bold fruit flavors. I added fruit to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/cherry-wine&#34;&gt;cherry wine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/pale-apricot-sour&#34;&gt;apricot sour&lt;/a&gt; very early in their fermentations, aiming for a depth of fruit flavors in the final products. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/dark-saison-i&#34;&gt;dark saison&lt;/a&gt; got zante currants as soon as it went into secondary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ll still brew that way occasionally in the future, but in general I&amp;rsquo;m going to start waiting for the base beer to mature, and then decide what further additions to make, if any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this case I&amp;rsquo;m going for a pale sour similar to my apricot sour, but I&amp;rsquo;ll hold off on any fruit additions at first. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the base beer will turn out complex, sour, and funky. When it&amp;rsquo;s ready, I&amp;rsquo;ll let its final character dictate where to go from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some fruit options I&amp;rsquo;m considering are peaches, sour cherries, blueberries, or wine grapes. I&amp;rsquo;ll also bottle some of it straight if it&amp;rsquo;s interesting on it&amp;rsquo;s own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pale Apricot Sour</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/pale-apricot-sour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/pale-apricot-sour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s sour time again! This type of beer has a long turnaround time, so I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get a lage pipeline going this winter. Hopefully next year I can start having somewhat regular releases of finished sours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This batch is inspired by Sapwood Cellars &lt;a href=&#34;https://untappd.com/b/sapwood-cellars-brewery-upper-bound-apricot/3636986&#34;&gt;Upper Bound: Apricot&lt;/a&gt;. It was the first first apricot sour I ever tried, and I thought it was fantastic. One of my favorite releases from them so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>