<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>American on Wallflower Brewing</title>
    <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/american/</link>
    <description>Recent content in American on Wallflower Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 16:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/american/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hazy Cryo Pale Ale</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/hazy-cryo-pale-ale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/hazy-cryo-pale-ale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/hazy-pale-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;finished beer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low-ish alcohol and big-ish flavor are the order of the day. I&amp;rsquo;m aiming for a sessionable ~5.3% hazy pale ale with lots of hop character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hop blend will be an old favorite of mine: amarillo, citra, and simcoe. But for something a little different, I&amp;rsquo;m going to use all cryo hops.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HBC 472 Oatmeal Stout</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/hbc-472-oatmeal-stout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/hbc-472-oatmeal-stout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/2020stout.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;finished beer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy almost winter! This batch will be an oatmeal stout to test out HBC 472 as a dark beer flavor hop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;472 is a newer hop with some pretty unusual taste descriptors: wood, coconut, vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to try an IPA that was dry hopped with this a little while ago. It was definitely different. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really get the wood/vanilla but there were some coconut notes. It was a bit odd in IPA form but I thought it might make a good dark beer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Wine Farmhouse Ale</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/white-wine-farmhouse-ale/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/white-wine-farmhouse-ale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s brew is going to be a pale beer/wine hybrid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, my approach for combining wine and beer has been to blend finished commercial wine into my beers at a rate between one cup, and a whole bottle in five gallons of beer. Results have been good, but a bit on the subtle side. Today I want to try to make something more wine forward &amp;ndash; a real beer/wine hybrid instead of just a beer with a little bit of wine in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whole grapes would be great for this, but that&amp;rsquo;s a large and expensive purchase. I&amp;rsquo;m going to need some planning and confidence when I do finally buy a 5 gallon pail of frozen grapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of whole grapes, for this batch I&amp;rsquo;m going to add the undiluted contents of a one gallon (~5 bottles) wine kit a few days into primary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homegrown Cascade IPA</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/homegrown-cascade-ipa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/homegrown-cascade-ipa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/homegrown-ipa/dry-hops.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dried hops&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eight years ago, Adrienne and I planted hop rhizomes in the corner of her parents garden: cascade, and nugget I think. Since then they&amp;rsquo;ve been neglected, growing kind of wild. We never trellised or harvested them. I thought they might not survive like this, but they seem to be hardy plants!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, a deer fence went up around the garden. The hops climbed all over it and produced an unexpected bounty. With so many hops just sitting there, I decided I&amp;rsquo;d finally try making a beer with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEIPA with Mosaic, Nelson, Hallertau Blanc</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/neipa-with-mosaic-nelson-hallertau-blanc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/neipa-with-mosaic-nelson-hallertau-blanc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/nelson-hallertau.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;finished beer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of my brewing ideas come from trying a great commercial beer and wanting to replicate its flavors at home. Today&amp;rsquo;s subject is Sapwood&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://untappd.com/b/sapwood-cellars-brewery-the-dragon/3566895&#34;&gt;The Dragon&lt;/a&gt; which used a hop blend that I had never tried before: Mosaic, Nelson Sauvin, and Hallertau Blanc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Nelson Sauvin and Hallertau Blanc are typically described as having wine-like qualities. Nelson Sauvin in particular has a reputation for being very unique, and a bit polarizing. I thought The Dragon was delicious though, so I guess I might be a fan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This won&amp;rsquo;t be a clone, just a recipe inspired by the hop blend from the original.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citra Session Ale</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/citra-session-ale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/citra-session-ale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/citra-session/finished.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;finished beer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some unlucky timing, both &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/experimenting-with-hop-blends&#34;&gt;DIPA variants&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch&#34;&gt;last kolsch&lt;/a&gt; all kicked within a couple days of each other this week. An empty kegerator is a sad thing. This is going to be a quick &amp;ldquo;what do I have on hand?&amp;rdquo; recipe. Happily, what I have on hand is a buch of citra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having NEIPA and DIPA on my hoppy taps for the last few months, I&amp;rsquo;m in the mood for something easier drinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m aiming for a nice light pale ale in the low 4% abv, moderate bitterness, and solid hop flavor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting With Hop Blends</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/experimenting-with-hop-blends/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/experimenting-with-hop-blends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/columbus-dipa-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;finished beer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is batch number two of my IPA experiment series. In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/galaxy-citra-neipa-experiment&#34;&gt;first batch&lt;/a&gt; I tested out some new equipment and techniques. The beers were some of the best IPAs I&amp;rsquo;ve ever made, but they were very hard to tell apart. It felt like I had one beer taking up two taps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe a bad sign for my motivation for testing small tweaks, but for this round I feel like having a litte fun and brewing two significantly different IPAs just to compare the hop blends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have ideas of what hops I like, but it&amp;rsquo;ll be nice to have two equally fresh beers to taste at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxy Citra NEIPA Experiment</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/galaxy-citra-neipa-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 16:11:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/galaxy-citra-neipa-experiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/citra-galaxy/finished.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;finished beer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my brewing goals for 2020 is to improve the quality of my IPAs. I feel like this far into the brewing game, I should have a little more to show for it when I make my favorite style. They&amp;rsquo;re rarely bad, but they don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;wow&lt;/em&gt; as often as I&amp;rsquo;d like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To that end I&amp;rsquo;m going to be doing a series of experiments this year where make two similar beers at the same time, with just one variable changed. I hope this will improve my process, one tweak at at time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this brew, I&amp;rsquo;m trying out some new hardware and techniques that I&amp;rsquo;ll use for the rest of my upcoming experiments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rye Barrel Stout</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/rye-barrel-stout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/rye-barrel-stout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/rye-stout/boil.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;We&amp;rsquo;re going to need a bigger fermenter&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This beer is the first brew to go into my 15 gallon Dad&amp;rsquo;s Hat rye whiskey barrel. That barrel is destined for sour solera duty, but first I want to brew a couple of big clean beers to make the most of the barrel&amp;rsquo;s fresh whiskey character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This stout is based on a KBS clone recipe from Zymurgy that I first brewed way back in 2013. That was a great beer, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to try making it again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>