<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kolsch on Wallflower Brewing</title>
    <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/kolsch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kolsch on Wallflower Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/kolsch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall Kolsch</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/fall-kolsch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/fall-kolsch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This batch will be very similar to my recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch-3&#34;&gt;Spring Kolsch 3&lt;/a&gt;. It was delicious, and brewing all extract was so refreshingly fast and easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be trying a few small changes that I thought might improve the beer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;24 IBU for ~20% less bitterness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slightly warmer ferment temp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reverse osmosis water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slightly higher OG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Kolsch 3</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another spring, another Kolsch. This is one of my favorite seasonal brewing traditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around I&amp;rsquo;m going to try a 100% extract version of this beer. For my last few brew days, I&amp;rsquo;ve done one all grain batch, and one extract. I can basically finish the extract beer while the mash is going for the all grain one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very time efficient. Brew two beers, but only really have to clean once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might be the simplest recipe I&amp;rsquo;ve ever made. Just light pils DME and some Hallertau hops.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Kolsch 2</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;imagefloatleft&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/kolsch2/small.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Kolsch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally brew two nearly identical beers so close together, but I was really enjoying the last batch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch&#34;&gt;kolsch&lt;/a&gt; when it kicked. Seeing how it&amp;rsquo;s still officially spring for a few more weeks, bring on &amp;ldquo;Spring Kolsch&amp;rdquo; round two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this batch I&amp;rsquo;m going to try a some of the changes I wanted to experiment with last time: Lower alcohol, and a hop bill of 100% Hallertau Mittelfrüh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recipe is pushing the limits of what the BJCP would consider a kolsch. Compared to the traditional styles guides, this beer is a bit too light on alcohol, and a bit too heavy with the hops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not planning to send this to any competitions though. I just want to brew the ideal interpretation of koslch for my tastes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Kolsch</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 16:11:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/spring.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;redbud flowers&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been homebrewing for nearly 10 years, but in that time I&amp;rsquo;ve only made one German beer, my recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/extract-kettle-sour-berliner-weisse&#34;&gt;Berliner Weisse&lt;/a&gt;. This neglect of the German styles needs to be rectified!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love kolsch, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been happy to see it gaining a small but significant popularity in the US in the last decade. I think the only reason I haven&amp;rsquo;t made one is just that I&amp;rsquo;ve been distracted making lots of English bitters/milds and Belgain wits to satisfy my low bitterness session beer needs. The time for Kolsch has arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When making a new style for the first time, I like to go with a trusted recipe. This beer is very close to The Mad Fermentationist&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themadfermentationist.com/2010/09/fall-kolsch-recipe.html&#34;&gt;Fall Kolsch&lt;/a&gt;. His example is on the bitter end for this style, but I think that will be to my liking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it&amp;rsquo;s the end of March, not early September, I&amp;rsquo;ll call my version &amp;ldquo;Spring Kolsch&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>