<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Session Beer on Wallflower Brewing</title>
    <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/session-beer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Session Beer on Wallflower Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 16:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/session-beer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hazy Cryo Pale Ale</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/hazy-cryo-pale-ale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/hazy-cryo-pale-ale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/hazy-pale-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;finished beer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low-ish alcohol and big-ish flavor are the order of the day. I&amp;rsquo;m aiming for a sessionable ~5.3% hazy pale ale with lots of hop character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hop blend will be an old favorite of mine: amarillo, citra, and simcoe. But for something a little different, I&amp;rsquo;m going to use all cryo hops.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Bitter</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/best-bitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/best-bitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/best-bitter/cotswolds.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;english field&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some beers can transport you to another time and place. English Bitter does that for me. I really came to appreciate the style a few years ago on a trip around England. The trip was a ton of fun, and I got to enjoy a variety of English ales in their traditional cask presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the styles I tried, Bitter was my favorite. Like many of the traditional English ales, it is flavorful, low in alcohol, and a refreshing change of pace for a palate that&amp;rsquo;s suffering a bit of IPA fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a sign that I&amp;rsquo;m getting old, but in the last few years I&amp;rsquo;ve gained much more appreciation for subtle beer &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;beer flavored beer&amp;rdquo;. Bitter is high in the running to be my overall favorite beer flavored beer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citra Session Ale</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/citra-session-ale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/citra-session-ale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/citra-session/finished.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;finished beer&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some unlucky timing, both &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/experimenting-with-hop-blends&#34;&gt;DIPA variants&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch&#34;&gt;last kolsch&lt;/a&gt; all kicked within a couple days of each other this week. An empty kegerator is a sad thing. This is going to be a quick &amp;ldquo;what do I have on hand?&amp;rdquo; recipe. Happily, what I have on hand is a buch of citra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having NEIPA and DIPA on my hoppy taps for the last few months, I&amp;rsquo;m in the mood for something easier drinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m aiming for a nice light pale ale in the low 4% abv, moderate bitterness, and solid hop flavor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Kolsch 2</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;imagefloatleft&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/kolsch2/small.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Kolsch!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally brew two nearly identical beers so close together, but I was really enjoying the last batch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch&#34;&gt;kolsch&lt;/a&gt; when it kicked. Seeing how it&amp;rsquo;s still officially spring for a few more weeks, bring on &amp;ldquo;Spring Kolsch&amp;rdquo; round two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this batch I&amp;rsquo;m going to try a some of the changes I wanted to experiment with last time: Lower alcohol, and a hop bill of 100% Hallertau Mittelfrüh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recipe is pushing the limits of what the BJCP would consider a kolsch. Compared to the traditional styles guides, this beer is a bit too light on alcohol, and a bit too heavy with the hops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not planning to send this to any competitions though. I just want to brew the ideal interpretation of koslch for my tastes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Kolsch</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 16:11:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/spring-kolsch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/spring.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;redbud flowers&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been homebrewing for nearly 10 years, but in that time I&amp;rsquo;ve only made one German beer, my recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/extract-kettle-sour-berliner-weisse&#34;&gt;Berliner Weisse&lt;/a&gt;. This neglect of the German styles needs to be rectified!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love kolsch, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been happy to see it gaining a small but significant popularity in the US in the last decade. I think the only reason I haven&amp;rsquo;t made one is just that I&amp;rsquo;ve been distracted making lots of English bitters/milds and Belgain wits to satisfy my low bitterness session beer needs. The time for Kolsch has arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When making a new style for the first time, I like to go with a trusted recipe. This beer is very close to The Mad Fermentationist&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themadfermentationist.com/2010/09/fall-kolsch-recipe.html&#34;&gt;Fall Kolsch&lt;/a&gt;. His example is on the bitter end for this style, but I think that will be to my liking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it&amp;rsquo;s the end of March, not early September, I&amp;rsquo;ll call my version &amp;ldquo;Spring Kolsch&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract Kettle Sour Berliner Weisse</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/extract-kettle-sour-berliner-weisse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 12:11:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/extract-kettle-sour-berliner-weisse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/starter-small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lacto starter&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/souring-small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Souring&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked Berliner Weisse, but never brewed one. And I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to experiment with kettle souring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The procedure I&amp;rsquo;m following comes from this great presentation by Derek Springer: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fivebladesbrewing.com/presentations/berliner-and-beyond-sour-mashing-and-its-applications/&#34;&gt;Berliner and Beyond: Sour Mashing and Its Applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a starter for your lacto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get your wort under 4.5 pH as soon as possible to deter unwanted microbes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hold at a happy temperature for your lacto strain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimize oxygen exposure by covering with plastic wrap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, boil, chill, and pitch yeast as normal to finish the beer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>