<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fruit on Wallflower Brewing</title>
    <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/fruit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fruit on Wallflower Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/fruit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rustic Saison</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/rustic-saison/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/rustic-saison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/rustic-saison/pellicle.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pellicle in secondary&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite styles these days is mixed fermentation tart saison. Earlier in the year I made my &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/saison-vinifera&#34;&gt;first attempt&lt;/a&gt; at brewing one myself. For that beer, I blended about 20% kettle soured berliner weisse to a saison that had brett, but no souring bacteria added. It isn&amp;rsquo;t finished yet, but from some gravity samples I think it&amp;rsquo;s going to end up being tasty, but not as tart as I expected from my blending tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my second go at the style, I&amp;rsquo;m going to use a full range of brett and souring bacteria. To hopefully get a light tartness instead of full-on souring, I&amp;rsquo;m going to mash low and wait until a few days into fermetation before adding the sour bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt;: After some intermediate samples I decided this beer could use some adjuncts to make things a bit more interesting. On the theme of native North American ingredients, I’m going to split the beer onto cranberries (cooked down with some red wine), blueberries, and local honey*. I’ll bottle what remains as-is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Saison I</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/dark-saison-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 12:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/dark-saison-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This batch continues the deep dive I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking into mixed fermentation brewing over the last 6 months. I have a bunch of sours in the pipeline now and I&amp;rsquo;d like to get some funky, non-sour, brett beers going. I brewed my first &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/saison-vinifera&#34;&gt;brett saison&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks ago. This will be my second attempt in the broad style of funky saison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themadfermentationist.com/2019/04/dark-funky-saison-retrospective.html&#34;&gt;10 year retrospective&lt;/a&gt; from The Mad Fermentationist&amp;rsquo;s yearly dark saison project was inspirational. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to keep up my own similar series. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll probably take inspiration from Mike and friends the first couple years, and then strike out with my own experimental brews as I get more comfortable with this style of funky brewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the standout beers from that tasting was year four&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themadfermentationist.com/2012/01/american-farmhouse-currant-dark-saison.html&#34;&gt;American Farmhouse Currant Dark Saison&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m going to brew that recipe for the first shot at this style.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pale Apricot Sour</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/pale-apricot-sour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/pale-apricot-sour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s sour time again! This type of beer has a long turnaround time, so I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get a lage pipeline going this winter. Hopefully next year I can start having somewhat regular releases of finished sours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This batch is inspired by Sapwood Cellars &lt;a href=&#34;https://untappd.com/b/sapwood-cellars-brewery-upper-bound-apricot/3636986&#34;&gt;Upper Bound: Apricot&lt;/a&gt;. It was the first first apricot sour I ever tried, and I thought it was fantastic. One of my favorite releases from them so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherry Wine</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/cherry-wine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 16:11:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/cherry-wine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Double sour brew day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still very new to sour beer brewing. Rather than going off and experimenting right away, I want to start with some proven recipes. Today I&amp;rsquo;m starting a couple of beers inspired by my favorite sours to come out of Sapwood Cellars to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, &lt;a href=&#34;https://untappd.com/b/sapwood-cellars-brewery-opulence/3497213&#34;&gt;Opulence&lt;/a&gt;, a sour red that has two separate cherry additions.  Aged in a mix of red wine and bourbon barrels, dry sour cherries were added early in the aging process, and then before bottling it was finished on fresh sour cherries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before trying it I was a little skeptical of combination of bourbon bourbon aging a sour beer, but the vanilla character of the barrels worked really nicely with the cherries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>