<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wine on Wallflower Brewing</title>
    <link>http://desktop/tags/wine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wine on Wallflower Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 16:11:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://desktop/tags/wine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Saison Vinifera</title>
      <link>http://desktop/saison-vinifera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 16:11:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://desktop/saison-vinifera/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vitis_vinifera&#34;&gt;Vitus Vinifera&lt;/a&gt; is the scientific name for the species that contains most varieties of wine grapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &amp;ldquo;Saison Vinifera&amp;rdquo; will blend funky tart saison, oak, and wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://desktop/img/sapwood-saisons-small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bottles of No Beginnings and First Blush&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large portion of my homebrewing over the last six months has been focused on trying to emulate the great mixed fermentation beers coming out of my favorite local brewery, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sapwoodcellars.com&#34;&gt;Sapwood Cellars&lt;/a&gt;. Two of those beers were delicious tart saisons that they released in fall 2019:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Beginnings&lt;/strong&gt; was a pale saison with Brettanomyces, aged in Sauvignon Blanc wine barrels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be willing to bet that &lt;strong&gt;First Blush&lt;/strong&gt; started life as a similar base beer to No Beginnings, but it was fermented with chardonnay &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomace&#34;&gt;pomace&lt;/a&gt;, and finished on whole Cabernet Franc grapes. It is rosé in appearance and the flavor has a unqiue light, tart fruitiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan is to brew a batch of funky pale saison, split it half in secondary, and see how close to each of these I can get&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherry Wine</title>
      <link>http://desktop/cherry-wine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 16:11:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://desktop/cherry-wine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Double sour brew day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still very new to sour beer brewing. Rather than going off and experimenting right away, I want to start with some proven recipes. Today I&amp;rsquo;m starting a couple of beers inspired by my favorite sours to come out of Sapwood Cellars to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, &lt;a href=&#34;https://untappd.com/b/sapwood-cellars-brewery-opulence/3497213&#34;&gt;Opulence&lt;/a&gt;, a sour red that has two separate cherry additions.  Aged in a mix of red wine and bourbon barrels, dry sour cherries were added early in the aging process, and then before bottling it was finished on fresh sour cherries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before trying it I was a little skeptical of combination of bourbon bourbon aging a sour beer, but the vanilla character of the barrels worked really nicely with the cherries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>