<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solera on Wallflower Brewing</title>
    <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/solera/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solera on Wallflower Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 20:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wallflowerbrewing.com/tags/solera/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Solera Red: Year Three</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/solera-red-year-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/solera-red-year-three/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/solera/barrel-year-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;solera barrel&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time for another solera update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be brewing two batches to get enough volume for this year. I expect to need about seven and a half gallons to refill the barrel and the rest will go into a keg for top ups. I&amp;rsquo;m pulling about half of the barrel&amp;rsquo;s volume this year instead of a third. The barrel is still tasting good, but I&amp;rsquo;m worried it might be starting to go in a direction I don&amp;rsquo;t like, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to pull some extra now while it&amp;rsquo;s still tasting nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I filled a keg last year for top ups, and I really liked the process of topping up from the keg. Unfortunately the beer in the keg ended up not tasting great, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to dump the old keg and try again with fresh beer this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to modify the solera to be a bit less sour so half of this year&amp;rsquo;s beer will be fermented without any lactic bacteria, just Sacch and Brett. I&amp;rsquo;ll be using Omega&amp;rsquo;s C2C Saison blend for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used C2C in the past and I think it made a perfect blending beer. No really loud flavors, just a subtle and pleasantly funky beer that melded really well with other sours. (It&amp;rsquo;s nice on its own too, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/saison-vinifera&#34;&gt;white wine saison&lt;/a&gt; I made with it is one of my favoite funky beers so far).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solera Red: Year Two</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/solera-red-year-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/solera-red-year-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/solera/barrel-year-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;solera barrel&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solera project is about to turn one year old. Before I can package the first year&amp;rsquo;s beer, I need get year two&amp;rsquo;s refill ready to go in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be brewing two batches to get enough volume for this year. I expect to need about six gallons to refill the barrel and the rest will age in a keg that I&amp;rsquo;ll use to keep the barrel topped up. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll get enough extra in the keg for about two years of top ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, top ups were the most error prone and annoying part of the barrel aging process. Each time I topped up the barrel, I had to rack the top up beer into smaller and smaller vessels to avoid leaving excessive headspace. In the end I wasted a lot of the top up beer, and the top up beer that remained at the end of the year didn&amp;rsquo;t taste great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storing the top up beer in a keg and topping up the barrel with a picnic tap should be a much nicer way to keep the barrel full. I&amp;rsquo;ll never have to rack the top up beer around again, and it&amp;rsquo;ll always be protected from oxygen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solera Red: Year One</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/solera-red-year-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/solera-red-year-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the recipe for my Flanders Red solera project as brewed in late 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a slightly Americanized take on the style, based on the &amp;ldquo;Wine Barrel Flemish Red&amp;rdquo; from American Sour Beers. I may change it a bit over the years as I see how the beer develops. I&amp;rsquo;ll link to any new posts related to this recipe in the notes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solera Red: Planning &amp; First Fill</title>
      <link>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/solera-red-planning-first-fill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wallflowerbrewing.com/solera-red-planning-first-fill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://wallflowerbrewing.com/img/rye-stout/barrel.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;fresh barrel&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been itching to start my own sour solera project ever since I started making sour beer. Barrels aren&amp;rsquo;t a requirement for a solera, lots of people make them in carboys or other vessels. But I have a romantic image of barrel aged beers and wanted to try the process for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to this project I&amp;rsquo;d never brewed with a barrel or even seriously considered getting one. I did a lot of background reading and I want to share what I learned getting ready for my project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;choose-a-barrel-size&#34;&gt;Choose a barrel size&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used barrels come in a wide variety of sizes. A standard American whiskey barrel is 53 gallons. Wine barrels are typically a little larger. 60 gallons is a common size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smaller barrels in the 5 to 30 gallon range are also available on the used market. Most come from small whiskey producers. I&amp;rsquo;m not aware of any sources for small wine barrels or if any wineries even use small barrels. It seems that if you want a small used barrel, you&amp;rsquo;re getting a whiskey barrel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>