<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solera on Wallflower Brewing</title>
    <link>http://desktop/tags/solera/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solera on Wallflower Brewing</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://desktop/tags/solera/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Solera Series Part 1: Planning &amp; First Fill</title>
      <link>http://desktop/solera-series-part-1-planning-first-fill/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://desktop/solera-series-part-1-planning-first-fill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://desktop/img/rye-stout/barrel.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;fresh barrel&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been itching to start my own sour solera project ever since I started making sour beer. Barrels aren&amp;rsquo;t a requirement for a solera, lots of people make them in carboys or other vessels. But I have a romantic image of barrel aged beers and wanted to try the process for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to this project I&amp;rsquo;d never brewed with a barrel or even seriously considered getting one. I did a lot of background reading and I want to share what I learned getting ready for my project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;choose-a-barrel-size&#34;&gt;Choose a barrel size&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used barrels come in a wide variety of sizes. A standard American whiskey barrel is 53 gallons. Wine barrels are typically a little larger. 60 gallons is a common size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smaller barrels in the 5 to 30 gallon range are also available on the used market. Most come from small whiskey producers. I&amp;rsquo;m not aware of any sources for small wine barrels or if any wineries even use small barrels. It seems that if you want a small used barrel, you&amp;rsquo;re getting a whiskey barrel.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solera Barrel Flanders Red</title>
      <link>http://desktop/solera-barrel-flanders-red/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://desktop/solera-barrel-flanders-red/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://desktop/img/solera/racking-1-small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;racking&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the recipe for my Flanders Red solera barrel as brewed in late 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty straightforward Flanders Red, based on the &amp;ldquo;Wine Barrel Flemish Red&amp;rdquo; from American Sour Beers. I may change it a bit over the years as I see how the beer develops. I&amp;rsquo;ll link to any new posts related to this recipe in the notes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>